DOUGLAS JAMES

WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

A web developer and musician that appreciates simple, beautiful websites. My experience producing music developed my passion for creating meaningful projects and solving complex problems efficiently. I love learning new technologies, designing excellent user experiences, and discovering new music.

EXPERIENCE

Dev Bootcamp, Graduate, Chicago

Apr 2016 - Aug 2016

Completed an intensive course comprising 1000+ hours learning Ruby, Rails, HTML5/CSS3, TDD, Javascript(JQuery,AJAX), Git, Heroku and Agile Development.

Co-created Repose, a mobile iOS app that helps users cope with and manage panic attacks. Languages and technologies used include Ruby on Rails, Xcode, Swift, Alamofire and Bootstrap.

PSAV, Technician, Chicago

Apr 2014 - Mar 2016

Audio setup, troubleshooting and operation with advanced knowledge of audio signal flow.

IT support including networking and DHCP.

Music Producer, Audio Engineer and Producer, Chicago

Jan 1990 - Current

Recorded, mixed and mastered hundreds of recording sessions for clients including: Iron and Wine, Sufjan Stevens and Chamber Strings. Created schedules and reviewed work for 8 person production teams.

Expert level experience with digital audio workstations.

PRF Graphics, Office Manager, Glenview, II

Jun 1988 - Mar 2014

Worked in accounts payable/accounts receivable providing customer service.

Administration of the computer network including network administration, desktop support and daily tape backup.

SKILLS

SKILLS: Ruby, Javascript(AJAX, JQuery), Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, HTML5/CSS3, Git, Heroku, ActiveRecord, Object Oriented Design, SQLite, Agile Development, TDD(RSpec, Jasmine, Capybara), Pro Tools

PROJECTS

Repose

A mobile application to help people cope with and manage their panic attacks and acute anxiety. It was created in one week as final project at Dev Bootcamp.

Contributions: Splash page, Functionality, Front End.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Xcode, Swift, Alamofire, Bootstrap.

repose.herokuapp.com/

github: https://github.com/duranje/repose-xcode

Dive Bookscamp

A client project for Dev Bootcamp. The app allows teachers to create a new schedule by participating in a snake-ordered live draft.

Contributions: Live draft functionality, Back End.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, Javascript(AJAX, JQuery).

dive-books-camp.herokuapp.com/

Github: https://github.com/zaki-arain/divebookscamp

ACTIVITIES

Voice Actor

Voice Over talent. Performed VO's on commercials by Motorola, McDonalds, Quill, etc.

EDUCATION

Dev Bootcamp 2016

Full SailAssociate of Science Recording Arts 2004